

# Michael Koch

## Software Developer

With over four years of exceptional software development experience. I bring a diverse and comprehensive understanding of all aspects of tech product development, including design, UX, and best coding practices. My proven track record of continuous learning and versatile skillset enables me to lead and deliver outstanding technical solutions to business problems. Coupled with strong interpersonal and collaborative skills, I excel at working with teams, facilitating discussions on product development, and driving projects to successful completion.

## Website (Portfolio):

michaelgkoch.com



mkoch@michaelgkoch.com



linkedin.com/in/michaelgkochh



@MichaelKochDev



856-404-8845

## Professional Experience

#### November 2023 – Present

## Freelance Software Development

As a freelance software developer, my projects and responsibilities include:

- Leading as the sole developer on multiple large-scale projects, I delivered customer-first products that drove revenue by managing UX design, backend functionality, frontend development, and database architecture
- Achieving user satisfaction and aligning with client business goals by integrating design principles, strategic product development, industry best coding practices, and maintaining clear communication and collaboration with clients and users to deliver impactful solutions
- Creating a cross-platform React Native app for the music industry, empowering artists to share and sell their music and merchandise directly to fans.
- Designing and building multiple high-converting landing pages that clearly communicate a business's purpose and drive user engagement

Experience: NextJS 14, Tailwind CSS, Node.js, MongoDB, APIs, AI (LLMs), Supabase, React Native

#### March 2023 - March 2024

#### Associate Software Engineer @ JP Morgan Chase

As an Associate Software Engineer for JP Morgan Chase, I am responsible for:

- Acting as Lead Front-End Developer by overseeing and producing all aspects related to user interface development.
- Accomplishing implementation upgrades to our UI, enabling users to perform more accurate data updates.
- Streamlining testing processes within our application, leading to more robust code coverage and efficient deployments
- Development of sophisticated automated functional tests to ensure proper integration and performance between our UI and API
- Maintenance of our CI/CD pipelines, resulting in effective deployments to production

Experience: React, Spring Boot, CI/CD, Junit, SQL, AWS, TDD, Agile, APIs

## May 2021 - March 2023

## Software Developer @ CCLR

As a Software Developer for CCLR, I am responsible for:

- Managing the automation and interconnection of multiple departments, leading to enhanced productivity and reduced human error.
- Driving revenue growth by conducting R&D on hand-serving automation and designing a brand new hand-serving subpoena technology from the ground up.
- Developing complex SQL queries of business data, while concurrently building an intuitive user interface for data visualization and manipulation
- Collaborating with management and employees to define business requirements, and subsequently deliver successfully on said requirements

Experience: JavaScript, ASP.NET, C#, jQuery, SQL, HTML

### June 2020 - August 2020

#### Web Development Intern @ Maxeta Technologies Inc.

As a Web Development Intern for Maxeta Technologies Inc., I am responsible for:

- Working with clients to outline and understand business problems.
- Helping develop an application that automates day-to-day tasks of client's employees, improving efficiency and organization company-wide.

Experience: Typescript, Angular

### Education

2017 - 2021 - Philadelphia

Temple University

BS In Computer Engineering & Minor in Computer Science

2022 - Online

Coursera

Machine Learning/AI Fundamentals

# Top Skills:

NextJS, React, JavaScript, C#, SQL, Java, CSS